TheaterWorks Records MS023
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Fundraising and grants, 1981 -- 1999; 1981 -- 1989; MS023.007; 1.45 Linear Feet
  This series contains box office documents, correspondences, mailing lists for subscribers, donor and contributor information, information from granting organization, copies of completed grant applications and funding proposals. The bulk of the information is from 1981-1989. These records show where TheaterWorks applied to for grants and donations: funds that covered the majority of the organizations expenses.
  This series is arranged topically.
  - Hamlet-group sales, 1985; MS023.007.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Subscriber info, 1983 -- 1984; MS023.007.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - [Correspondence], 1983; MS023.007.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Old mailing lists, 1985; MS023.007.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Fundraising, 1986 -- 1988; MS023.007.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Waltham News Tribune, 1983 -- 1984; MS023.007.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Mailing lists, 1986; MS023.007.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - [Donor cards], 1982 -- 1983; MS023.007.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - Outside donors, 1982 -- 1983; MS023.007.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Development-key prospects individuals, 1983; MS023.007.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Donaters, 1984; MS023.007.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Donaters/contributors, 1986 -- 1987; MS023.007.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Donations, 1987 -- 1988; MS023.007.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - Somerville arts council, 1984; MS023.007.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Somerville arts lottery, 1985 -- 1986; MS023.007.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - 1983 application [Boston], MS023.007.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - Boston arts lottery, 1985; MS023.007.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Boston arts lottery, Somerville arts, 1983 -- 1985; MS023.007.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - Boston arts lottery, 1987 -- 1988; MS023.007.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - Ma. cultural alliance, 1989; MS023.007.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - Grants (non-MCAH/Arts lottery), 1987 -- 1988; MS023.007.007.00021 (Box 7)
  - Insentive grant, 1985; MS023.007.007.00022 (Box 7)
  - New works, 1982; MS023.007.007.00023 (Box 7)
  - Development-local, 1982 -- 1983; MS023.007.007.00024 (Box 7)
  - WB2 fund arts, 1984; MS023.007.007.00025 (Box 7)
  - Fundraising-NEA, 1983 -- 1984; MS023.007.007.00026 (Box 7)
  - NEA, 1984; MS023.007.007.00027 (Box 7)
  - Promotion-notices, 1983; MS023.007.007.00028 (Box 7)
  - Associated grantmakers of MA, 1984; MS023.007.007.00029 (Box 7)
  - Mass. council, 1983 -- 1984; MS023.007.007.00030 (Box 7)
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts council on the arts and humanities, biennial report, 1981 -- 1982; MS023.007.007.00031 (Box 7)
  - Som. Arts, 1986; MS023.007.007.00032 (Box 7)
  - Arts Boston, 1986; MS023.007.007.00033 (Box 7)
  - Long proposals, 1985; MS023.007.007.00034 (Box 7)
  - Grant info, 1987; MS023.007.007.00035 (Box 7)
  - Mass council-New works, 1982 -- 1983; MS023.007.007.00036 (Box 7)
  - 84-85 Grants-originals, 1984 -- 1985; MS023.007.007.00037 (Box 7)
  - Fundraising-Mass, 1984; MS023.007.007.00038 (Box 7)
  - Mass. council-incentive grant, 1983; MS023.007.007.00039 (Box 7)
  - Dev. Individuals, 1983; MS023.007.007.00040 (Box 7)
  - TheaterWorks, 1984; MS023.007.007.00041 (Box 7)
  - Incentive, 1985; MS023.007.007.00042 (Box 7)
  - MA council on arts and hum., 1983 -- 1985; MS023.007.007.00043 (Box 7)
  - Mass Cultural Alliance, 1983; MS023.007.007.00044 (Box 7)
  - NEFA, 1986; MS023.007.007.00045 (Box 7)
  - Merit aid application (copy), Mass council on arts and humanities, 1985 -- 1986; MS023.007.007.00046 (Box 7)
  - Merit aid application notes, 1986 -- 1987; MS023.007.007.00047 (Box 7)
  - Merit aid application [1 complete copy], 1985; MS023.007.007.00048 (Box 7)
  - Merit aid application leftover material, 1985; MS023.007.007.00049 (Box 7)
  - [The grantsmanship center whole nonprofit catalog], 1987; MS023.007.007.00050 (Box 7)
  - [Multiple funders], 1987 -- 1989; MS023.007.007.00051 (Box 7)
  - Fundraising info, 1983; MS023.007.007.00052 (Box 7)
  - Tanne Foundation grants paperwork [1 of 2], 1999; MS023.007.009.00001 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
    This grant paperwork provides an excellent summary of the history of TheaterWorks.
  - Tanne Foundation grants paperwork [2 of 2], 1999; MS023.007.009.00002 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
- Publicity and media, 1976 -- 2010; 1976 -- 1990; MS023.008; 1.7 Linear Feet
  This series contains originals for brochures, letterhead, logos, printing, forms, and oversized posters. It also contains press clippings including ones mounted for display, others that are pasted-up originals and archival originals (copies). There are also TheaterWorks magazines and newsletters, PR and press listings, marketing documents and press packets. The records are spread out over the inclusive dates. Most of these records were created as part of marketing and publicity campaigns for specific productions or events.
  - Brochures, 1986; MS023.008.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - [Logo], 1980 -- 1990; MS023.008.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - [Letterhead and cards], 1980 -- 1990; MS023.008.008.00003 (Box 8)
    Also contains a letter from 1982 from US Representative John Joseph Moakley.
  - Chorus, 1983 -- 1984; MS023.008.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Printing originals, 1981 -- 1985; MS023.008.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Forms-original, 1980 -- 1990; MS023.008.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Originals-T.W., 1982 -- 1983; MS023.008.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Press 76-77 Pastups/copies, 1976 -- 1977; MS023.008.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - 76-77 archival originals, 1976 -- 1977; MS023.008.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - Press 77-78 copies and pasteups, 1977 -- 1978; MS023.008.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - 77-78 archival originals, 1977 -- 1978; MS023.008.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - Press 78-79 Pasteups and copies, 1978 -- 1979; MS023.008.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - 78-79 archival originals, 1978 -- 1979; MS023.008.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - Press 79-80 Pasteups and copies, 1979 -- 1980; MS023.008.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - 79-80 archival originals, 1979 -- 1980; MS023.008.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - Reviews 80-81 pasteups/copies, 1980 -- 1981; MS023.008.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - Press 80-81 originals (archival), 1980 -- 1981; MS023.008.008.00017 (Box 8)
  - Reviews 81-82 pasteups and copies, 1981 -- 1982; MS023.008.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - Press 81-82 archival masters, 1981 -- 1982; MS023.008.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - Reviews 82-83 pasteups/copies, 1982 -- 1983; MS023.008.008.00020 (Box 8)
  - Press 82-83 masters, 1982 -- 1983; MS023.008.008.00021 (Box 8)
  - Reviews 83-84, 1983 -- 1984; MS023.008.008.00022 (Box 8)
  - 83-84 archival masters, 1983 -- 1984; MS023.008.008.00023 (Box 8)
  - Power plays archival copies, 1984; MS023.008.008.00024 (Box 8)
  - Reviews 84-85, 1984 -- 1985; MS023.008.008.00025 (Box 8)
  - 84-85 archival masters, 1984 -- 1985; MS023.008.008.00026 (Box 8)
  - Reviews 85-86, 1985 -- 1986; MS023.008.008.00027 (Box 8)
  - Press 85-86 masters, 1985 -- 1986; MS023.008.008.00028 (Box 8)
  - Reviews 86-87, 1986 -- 1987; MS023.008.008.00029 (Box 8)
  - Press 1986-87 masters, 1986 -- 1987; MS023.008.008.00030 (Box 8)
  - Press 87-88 pasteups and copies, 1987 -- 1988; MS023.008.008.00031 (Box 8)
  - Press 87-88 masters, 1987 -- 1988; MS023.008.008.00032 (Box 8)
  - Press 88-89 pasteups and copies, 1988 -- 1989; MS023.008.008.00033 (Box 8)
  - Press 88-89 masters, 1988 -- 1989; MS023.008.008.00034 (Box 8)
  - Press 89-90 pasteups/mailings-brochures, 1989 -- 1990; MS023.008.008.00035 (Box 8)
  - 89 Press masters, 1989 -- 1990; MS023.008.008.00036 (Box 8)
  - [Mounted clippings], 1984 -- 1986; MS023.008.008.00037 (Box 8)
  - TheaterWorks magazine, 1983; MS023.008.008.00038 (Box 8)
  - Audience develop., 1982; MS023.008.008.00039 (Box 8)
  - Originals press clips, 1981 -- 1982; MS023.008.008.00040 (Box 8)
  - Press relations and correspondence, 1981 -- 1984; MS023.008.008.00041 (Box 8)
  - Originals-press clippings, 1982 -- 1983; MS023.008.008.00042 (Box 8)
  - Press clips-originals-old and new, 1982; MS023.008.008.00043 (Box 8)
  - Publicity, 1981 -- 1982; MS023.008.008.00044 (Box 8)
  - Old/other press lists, 1980 -- 1990; MS023.008.008.00045 (Box 8)
  - Publicity, 1981 -- 1984; MS023.008.008.00046 (Box 8)
  - Press/PR, 1980 -- 1990; MS023.008.008.00047 (Box 8)
  - Marketing (file), 1983; MS023.008.009.00003 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Marketing, general, 1980 -- 1990; MS023.008.009.00004 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Key results management, 1983; MS023.008.009.00005 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Pathways-Wilso, 1985; MS023.008.009.00006 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Newsletter (back), 1988; MS023.008.009.00007 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - [Press packet-Mensch Meier], 1986; MS023.008.009.00008 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - [Press packet-Mensch Meier], 1986; MS023.008.009.00009 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Subscription/ticket order, 1980 -- 1990; MS023.008.009.00010 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Subscribers, 1988; MS023.008.009.00011 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Greater Boston media directory, 1982 -- 1983; MS023.008.009.00012 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - The Boston Globe Calendar, Oct 1 and Oct 29, 1987; MS023.008.009.00013 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - The Boston Ledger Vol 49 #38 Sept 27-Oct 3, 1986; MS023.008.009.00014 (Box MS023 Shared 3)
  - Markups and display materials, 1983; MS023.008.015.00002 (Box Shared 126)
  - Original for TheaterWorks-In Progress Poster, 1988; MS023.008.015.00003 (Box Shared 126)
  - Originals for Out Out poster and flyer, 1983; MS023.008.015.00004 (Box Shared 126)
  - Mounted clippings, 1981 -- 1982; MS023.008.015.00005 (Box Shared 126)
  - Original publicity for Idol Cooking, 1988; MS023.008.015.00006 (Box Shared 126)
  - Original posters and brochures, 1988; MS023.008.015.00007 (Box Shared 126)
  - Original brochure and newsletter, 1986; MS023.008.015.00008 (Box Shared 126)
  - TheaterWorks alumni clippings, programs, and fliers, 1983 -- 2002; MS023.000447 (Box Shared 145, Folder 9)
    Material related to Paul Shakespear, Janet Kenney, Jon Lipsky, Steve Cummings, Deborah Fortson, George Capaccio, and Kathleen Donohue.
  - Playbills, fliers, and newsletters, 1987 -- 2010; MS023.000448 (Box Shared 145, Folder 10)
    TheaterWorks brochures; "Beating Hearts and Inquiring Minds" mailer; publicity material from "Accidental Death of An Anarchist," "The Complete Guide to Idol Cooking," "Baby Steps," and "Bad Water;" and newsletters.
  - Posters, 1987 -- 1988; MS023.000449 (Box Shared 126)
    Posters from "Kaspar" and Spring 1988 performances.
- Audio/Visual media, 1975 -- 1990; MS023.009; 5 Audiovisual Object(s)
  This series contains reel-to-reel, VHS, KCA60 videotape and audiotape recordings of selected productions, and recordings for sound design including effects and musical cues. The records span the inclusive dates. Some of these records were created to be used in productions and others were created as records of the productions, including some collaborative projects with Idaho Shakespeare Festival.
  This series is arranged largely alphabetically.
  - Billy the Kid, final tape, 1978; MS023.009.010.00001 (Reel 10)
    7 1/2 ips 1/4 track stereo
    audio tape
  - Master-Enough Mussorgsky plus "Starving Class", 1901 -- 1980; MS023.009.010.00002 (Reel 10)
    Stereo 3 3/4 ips
  - Hamlet Burton: letter sc Now I am Alone, 1912 -- 1980; MS023.009.010.00003 (Reel 10)
  - Kaspar source tape 1 side one only, 1902 -- 1987; MS023.009.010.00004 (Reel 10)
  - Kaspar Tape I, 1987; MS023.009.010.00005 (Reel 10)
  - Kaspar Tape II (R-2-R Edit), 1987; MS023.009.010.00006 (Reel 10)
  - Master of Ecstasy-sound cues, 1987; MS023.009.010.00007 (Reel 10)
    7 1/2 ips
  - Tape 2 - Sources - Side 1 only, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.010.00008 (Reel 10)
  - TheaterWorks Kaspar, 1904 -- 1987; MS023.009.010.00009 (Reel 10)
    Maxell RX pro 120 VHS tape
    videocassette
  - Kaspar Preshow and intermission text - final, 1987; MS023.009.010.00010 (Reel 10)
    Maxell epilaxial XLII 60
    audiocassette
  - Kaspar SC 65A int text, 1987; MS023.009.010.00011 (Reel 10)
    Maxell epilaxial XLII 90
  - Pathways Tape 1, 1982; MS023.009.011.00001 (Reel 11)
    Scotch
  - Pathways 1505 songs tape 2, 1982; MS023.009.011.00002 (Reel 11)
    Radio shack
  - Pathways to madness Tape #2, 1982; MS023.009.011.00003 (Reel 11)
    Sony 7 1/2 ips tails out
  - Stage hoses Pathways B tape, 1982; MS023.009.011.00004 (Reel 11)
  - Richard Tape one, 1984; MS023.009.011.00005 (Reel 11)
  - Richard Tape one and swg x3, 1984; MS023.009.011.00006 (Reel 11)
  - Richard material - Richard Tape Two, 1984; MS023.009.011.00007 (Reel 11)
  - Richard III Fun Q, 1984; MS023.009.011.00008 (Reel 11)
  - Richard ghost stuff, 1984; MS023.009.011.00009 (Reel 11)
    JVC F1/90
  - Vatslav Alice #1, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.012.00001 (Reel 12)
    Radioshack
  - Vatslav! Alice #2, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.012.00002 (Reel 12)
    Maxell
  - Vatslav AB-4, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.012.00003 (Reel 12)
  - Winter's tale Act two- Tape one Act II, 1984; MS023.009.012.00004 (Reel 12)
  - 2 Gents raw footage (tape 1), 1984; MS023.009.012.00005 (Reel 12)
  - 2 Gents RR Two Tape II Acts 1 and 2, 1984; MS023.009.012.00006 (Reel 12)
  - 2 Gents Act one, tape 1 - Master Act I, 1984; MS023.009.012.00007 (Reel 12)
  - 2 Gents Act two, tape 1, 1984; MS023.009.012.00008 (Reel 12)
  - [Musical accompaniment] Side 1: Softly as a summer breeze; Side 2: Midnight special, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.013.00001 (Reel 13)
  - Vinny tape, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.013.00002 (Reel 13)
    Maxell; Springsteen, Jarrett, Paul Winter Consort, Lateef,
  - [Musical accompaniment], 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.013.00003 (Reel 13)
    Songs of the humpback whale, Celtic Harp, Think about your troubles, A little touch of Schmellson, A patch of blue, Paul Winter, Land of make believe, gorilla James Sweety, Gordon Lightfoot, Tom Waits, Shankar and Previn.
  - "911" Chris Rohmann, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.013.00004 (Reel 13)
    7 1/2 /sec-mono
  - Winter's Tale, Act one, Tape one, 1984; MS023.009.013.00005 (Reel 13)
  - Winter's Tale, RR two, Tape 2, Acts 1 and 2, 1984; MS023.009.013.00006 (Reel 13)
    Ampex
  - Original, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.013.00007 (Reel 13)
    Box contains significant notation; Ampex studio quality recording tape 7 inch reel.
  - Patch of blue, Keith Jarrett, 1975 -- 1989; MS023.009.013.00008 (Reel 13)
    Old West
  - [Unlabeled Scotch Recording Tape 7 1/2 ips 45 min. 5 inch reel], 1980 -- 1990; MS023.009.014.00001 (Reel 14)
  - This is a Blue reel. This is a master tape, 1980 -- 1990; MS023.009.014.00002 (Reel 14)
  - Shadow performance Tape #1, 1981; MS023.009.014.00003 (Reel 14)
  - Shadow Tape two, 1981; MS023.009.014.00004 (Reel 14)
  - S' Sister part 1, titles, 1983; MS023.009.014.00005 (Reel 14)
    Maxell KCA60
  - Scheherazade's Sister Part II, 1983; MS023.009.014.00006 (Reel 14)
  - Scheherazade's Sister Act 1, 1983; MS023.009.014.00007 (Reel 14)
- Unprocessed accessions, 1982; MS023.010; 1 Volumes
  - "Pathways to Madness" slides and video reel, 1982; MS023-001 (Box 1)